A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Catalogued Reports, Reports 6262-9286 FA739C
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Statement before House Committee on Interstate and Foreign Commerce, July 18 (Reports 006566), 1969 (Box 295)
  The paradox between commercial television and educational or public television is that commercial television ahs the resources, both professional and economic, to do magnificent programs, but not enough air time to pursue excellence.
  7 p. -- 28 cm
  Public broadcasting -- United States -- Law and legislation; Public television -- United States -- Law and legislation; Communication policy -- United States; Public television -- United States; Friendly, Fred W.; Ford Foundation. Public Broadcasting
- The Ford Foundation and Indonesia: 1953-1969 retrospect and prospect (Reports 006567) (Box 295)
  24 p.: tables, chart
  Charity organization -- Indonesia -- Evaluation; Educational assistance -- Indonesia; Endowments -- Indonesia -- Evaluation; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Management; Miller, Frank Justus; Ford Foundation; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific
- Development experience during periods of social and political change: Indonesia, 1960-1970 (Reports 006568) (Box 295)
  Social planning -- Indonesia; Nationalism -- Indonesia; Miller, Frank Justus; Ford Foundation; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific
- Benefit of the experience of Colombia for the development of Indonesia: Several impressions concerning the development policy of Colombia (Reports 006569), 1970 (Box 295)
  Confidential report from Indonesia Ambassador Soedjatmoko to Indonesia's Foreign Minister Adam Malik. --p. [1].
  Social planning -- Indonesia; Rural development -- Indonesia; Urbanization -- Indonesia; Economic development -- Indonesia; Social planning -- Colombia; Rural development -- Colombia; Urbanization -- Colombia; Soedjatmoko, 1922-1989; Ford Foundation; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific
- The Ford Foundation program in Indonesia (Reports 006570), 1969 (Box 295)
  Charity organization -- Indonesia; Economic assistance -- Indonesia; Technical assistance -- Indonesia; Social planning -- Indonesia; Endowments -- Indonesia -- Evaluation; Philanthropy -- Indonesia; Ford Foundation
- Ford Foundation activities in Southeast Asia (Reports 006571), 1971 (Box 295)
  6 p.: ill., table, chart
  Charity organization -- Southeast Asia; Endowments -- Southeast Asia -- Evaluation; Miller, Frank Justus; Ford Foundation. Field Office Bangkok; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific
- Financial aid pertaining to the U.N. and U.N. specialized agencies and to other broadly international governmental organizations (Reports 006572), 1969 (Box 295)
  10 p.: principally tables
  Administrative agencies -- Finance; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Finance; Endowments -- Evaluation; Gordon, Stanley; United Nations; Ford Foundation
- Comparative research and development training by UN and by other international governmental organizations (Reports 006573), 1969 (Box 295)
  Administrative agencies -- Developing countries -- Research; Gordon, Stanley; Ford Foundation. International Division; United Nations
- Indonesia (Reports 006574), 1954 (Box 295)
  6 p.: tables
  Education -- Indonesia; Education, Higher -- Indonesia; Education and state -- Indonesia; Higher education and state -- Indonesia; Agriculture -- Indonesia; Agriculture and state -- Indonesia; Economics -- Research -- Indonesia; Social sciences -- Research; Howard, John Brooks; Ford Foundation; Ford Foundation. Overseas Development Program
- Newsletter (from Indonesia) (Reports 006575), 1954 (Box 295)
  Agriculture -- Study and teaching -- Indonesia; English language -- Study and teaching -- Indonesia; Education -- Indonesia; Ford Foundation
- English language teaching, Auguast (Reports 006576), 1954 (Box 295)
  English language -- Study and teaching -- Indonesia; Education and state -- Indonesia; Howard, John Brooks; Ford Foundation
- A progress report from the Ensmingers of India (Reports 006577), 1953 (Box 295)
  8 leaves + attachment
  Social sciences -- Research -- India; Ensminger, Mary; Ensminger, Douglas, 1910-1989; Ford Foundation. Overseas Development Program
- New textbooks for Iran (Reports 006578), 1960 (Box 295)
  05900391
  Franklin Book Programs, Inc.
  Revision of Iranian textbooks.
  15 p. + attachment
  Textbooks -- Iran; Education -- Iran -- Curricula; Curriculum planning -- Iran; Educational planning -- Iran; Education and state -- Iran; Buck, Byron; Ford Foundation. Overseas Development Program; Iran. Vizārat-i Āmūzish va Parvarish
- Directory of selected donors (Reports 006579), 1976 (Box 295)
  Board of Trustees
  Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- Directories; Non-governmental organizations -- Directories; Ford Foundation Program development
- Private foundations and governmental attitudes: 1985 (Reports 006580), 1976 (Box 295)
  Board of Trustees;Office of the Secretary and General Counsel
  Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- Law and legislation -- United States; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Finance; Ginsburg, David, 1912-2010; Dressner, Howard R.; Ford Foundation. Office of the Secretary and General Counsel; Ford Foundation. Board of Trustees
- Mid-career fellowship for journalists in education: An evaluation (Reports 006581), 1976 (Box 295)
  Office of Communications
  41 p.
  Journalists -- Training of -- United States; Journalism, Educational -- United States -- Finance; Journalism, Educational -- Study and teaching; Journalism and education -- United States; Krueger, Starry; Ford Foundation. Office of Communications
- Preliminary bibliography of research in programmed instruction (Reports 006582), 1962 (Box 295)
  05500121
  The Leland Stanford Junior University
  Practical utilization of the behavioral sciences.
  [133 p.]
  Programmed instruction -- Research -- Bibliography; Programmed instruction -- United States -- Bibliography; Psychology -- Research -- Bibliography; Social sciences -- Research -- Bibliography; Schramm, Wilbur, 1907-1987; Ford Foundation. Special Programs
- Update of the India program for the 1954-56 planning period (Reports 006584) (Box 295)
  Discusses development planning in India and Foundation support for it.
  Charity organization -- India; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Finance; Endowments -- India -- Evaluation; Philanthropy -- India; Ensminger, Douglas, 1910-1989
- Request for summary of work done since February 1955 to 1960 (Reports 006585) (Box 295)
  Report on the footwear industry in India.
  Footwear industry -- India; Beyrodt, Erich; Ford Foundation. South and Southeast Asia
- Mapping change: using a theory of change to guide planning evaluation (Reports 006586), 2006 (Box 295)
  "This brief guide explains why grant makers use theories of change to guide their questioning, unearth assumptions that underlie their work, establish common language, and develop strong action plans. Contributors to the guide also describe how a theory o
  Peace and Social Justice/Office of the Vice President
  GrantCraft: practical wisdom for grantmakers
  Social planning -- Handbooks, manuals, etc.; Endowments -- Handbooks, manuals, etc.; Philanthropy -- Ways and means; Research grants -- Case studies; Endowment of research; GrantCraft.; GrantCraft.
- The recent economic evolution of the Sahel (Reports 006587), 1975 (Box 295)
  xi, 247 p.: ill. -- 28 cm.
  Economics -- Research -- Sahel; Economic development -- Sahel; Economic development -- Africa, West; Berg, Elliot
- International studies in Italy (Reports 006589), 1968 (Box 295)
  81 p.
  Foreign study -- Italy; Political science -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Italy; International relations -- Study and teaching (Higher); Education, Higher -- Italy -- Curricula; Silj, Alessandro, 1935-
- An evaluation of the Economics Institute (Reports 006590), 1961 (Box 296)
  24 p.: table
  Economics -- Study and teaching (Graduate) -- United States -- Evaluation; Economists -- Training of -- United States; College teachers -- Training of -- United States; Education (Graduate) -- United States; Universities and colleges -- United States; Hunter, Holland; Economics Institute; University of Colorado Boulder
- Staff responses to Alexander Heard's September 24 memorandum, "Next steps in planning for the Foundation's future" (Reports 006591), 1976 (Box 296)
  2 v.: various pagings
  Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Management; Charity organization; Ford Foundation Program development
- Report to the Ford Foundation on black political participation in the 1980 presidential selection process (Reports 006592), 1981 (Box 296)
  08050613
  Howard University
  Support for research project on black political behavior and the Democratic National Convention to be conducted by the Institute of Urban Affairs/Research.
  139 p.: principally tables, forms
  African Americans -- Politics and government -- Research; Political conventions -- United States; Party affiliation -- United States; Elections -- United States; Walters, Ronald W.; Ford Foundation. National Affairs
- Report of the Subcommittee on Information and Management in the Ford Foundation (Reports 006593), 1975 (Box 296)
  44 p. + appendix: tables
  Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Finance; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Management; Trottenberg, Arthur D., 1917-; Ford Foundation; Ford Foundation Management
- Possible cost reductions for program related information and grant administration systems (Reports 006594), 1975 (Box 296)
  Public Policy and Social Organization
  90 p.
  Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Finance; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Management; Sharpe, Richard S.; Ford Foundation. Public Policy and Social Organization; Ford Foundation; Ford Foundation Management
- Population office: program review and funding request for FY 1980-1981 (Reports 006595), 1979 (Box 296)
  Population assistance; Population policy; Birth control research; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Management; Ford Foundation. Population Office
- Report on Ford Foundation consultancy, Asia and Pacific Area (Reports 006596), 1981 (Box 297)
  Memo to John Bresnan, William Carmichael and Francis Sutton, dated May 4, 1981.
  Charity organization -- East Asia; Philanthropy -- East Asia; Baker, Alison, 1939-; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific
- Discussion of possible American adaptation of the British system of citizen's advice bureaus. (Reports 006597), 1966 (Box 297)
  Transcript of conference held February 10, 1966.
  06600097
  The Trustees of Columbia University in the City of New York
  Study of the feasibility of adapting the British citizens' advice bureaus for the United States.
  157 p.
  Citizens' advisory committees -- United States; Citizens' advisory committees -- Great Britain; Political planning -- United States -- Citizen participation; Political planning -- Great Britain -- Citizen participation; Social planning -- United States; Ford Foundation. National Affairs; The Trustees of Columbia University in the City of New York
- Vietnam foreign relations: A short history (Reports 006598), 1974 (Box 297)
  Vietnamese -- Ethnic identity; Vietnamese -- Ethnic relations; Ethnology -- Vietnam; Benoit, Charles E.; Ford Foundation. International Division
- Report on visit to Cairo, with special reference to the developing diploma and MSC programme in computer science at the Institute of Statistical Studies and Research and the implications of this development (Reports 006599), 1974 (Box 297)
  Computer science -- Study and teaching (Graduate) -- Egypt; Education (Graduate) -- Egypt; Buckingham, Richard A., 1922-; Ford Foundation. Field Office Cairo; Ford Foundation. Middle East and Africa
- Final report to the Ford Foundation (Reports 006600), 1973 (Box 297)
  06700219
  Arab Republic Of Egypt (Ministry Of Foreign Affairs)
  Establishment of a national computer center for scientific research and training at Cairo University.
  Computer science -- Study and teaching (Graduate) -- Egypt; Education (Graduate) -- Egypt; Van Belle, Gerald; Ford Foundation. Field Office Cairo; Ford Foundation. Middle East and Africa
- Report to Ford Foundation on visit to Institute of Statistical Studies and Research: Cairo University (Reports 006601), 1972 (Box 297)
  Statistics -- Study and teaching (Graduate) -- Egypt; Education (Graduate) -- Egypt; Durkin, Joseph T. (Joseph Thomas), 1903-2003; Ford Foundation. Field Office Cairo; Ford Foundation. Middle East and Africa
- IFAN Institut français d'Afrique noire, University of Dakar: preparation of a bi-lingual West African atlas (Reports 006602), 1973 (Box 297)
  06500301
  University of Dakar
  Preparation and publication of a West African Atlas by the University's Institut Fondamental d'Afrique Noire.
  8 leaves -- 28 cm.
  Publishers and publishing -- Africa, West; Map publishing -- Africa, West; LeBlond, Robert; Institut français d'Afrique noire
- Gift of the Greater Ganga: an approach to the integrated development of the Ganga-Brahmaputra Basin (Reports 006603), 1977 (Box 297)
  Lecture at India International Center, New Delhi, December 10, 1977.
  07950007
  Food Research Institute research work related to the agricultural productivity of the Indus Basin System in Pakistan.
  57 p.
  Watershed management -- Ganges River Watershed (India and Bangladesh); Watershed management -- India; Watershed management -- Bangladesh; Agricultural productivity -- India; Agricultural productivity -- Bangladesh; Verghese, B. G.; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific
- Report on trip to Pakistan (Reports 006604), 1976 (Box 297)
  Report on trip to Pakistan in conjunction with a research project on women's opportunities for education and its resultant impact on their social roles.
  Women -- Education -- Pakistan; Sex role -- Pakistan; Smock, Audrey C.
- Report of work completed on agricultural policy and regional planning in Pakistan (Reports 006605), 1978 (Box 297)
  Research projects were on fertilizer distribution and use in Sind, improving policy analysis in the Ministry of Food and Agriculture, statistical analysis and regional planning, cotton maximization project and teaching.
  Asia and the Pacific;Developing Countries Program;India, Nepal and Sri Lanka
  07300157
  University Of Karachi
  Support for the Applied Economics Research Centre.
  Agriculture and state -- Pakistan; Economics -- Study and teaching -- Pakistan; Regional planning -- Pakistan; Wallace, Michael B.; University Of Karachi
- Applied Economics Research Centre in mid 1978 (Reports 006606) (Box 297)
  Evaluation of the centre and recommendations for further support.
  07550157
  Economics -- Research -- Pakistan; Fiscal policy -- Pakistan; Gillis, Malcolm; University of Karachi. Applied Economics Research Centre
- An evaluation of Ford Foundation assistance to agriculture in Pakistan 1965-1979 (Reports 006607) (Box 297)
  07790807
  Program activities in the econonmics of agriculture in Pakistan.
  29 p. + attachment
  Agricultural assistance -- Pakistan -- Evaluation; Agriculture -- Economic aspects -- Pakistan; Endowments -- Pakistan -- Evaluation; Philanthropy -- Pakistan; Albrecht, H. R. (Herbert Richard), 1909-; Goldman, Richard H.; Sadiq, Mohammed; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific
- An informal note on Ford-funded research and training programme (Reports 006608), 1975 (Box 297)
  Informal attempt to describe the progress and the plans of the Applied Economics Research Centre.
  International Division/Asia and the Pacific;Developing Countries Program;India, Nepal and Sri Lanka
  Economics -- Research -- Pakistan; University of Karachi. Applied Economics Research Centre; University of Katachi. Applied Economics Research Centre.
- Evaluation report of the Ford Foundation grant no. 770-0075 to the Institute of Development Economics, Islamabad (Reports 006609), 1978 (Box 297)
  Evaluation of a grant given in support of a training program for upgrading the skills of officers working in planning positions in the provincial governments.
  07700075
  Pakistan Institute Of Development Economics
  Conducting of project planning training courses for provincial officials with assistance from the Project Planning Centre.
  20 p. + appendices: tables
  Central planning -- Pakistan; Provincial governments -- Pakistan; Endowments -- Pakistan -- Evaluation; Philanthropy -- Pakistan; Hussain, Syed M.; Ali, Chaudhri Muhammad; Killick, A. J.; Pakistan Institute of Development Economics
- A preliminary analysis of production factors limiting rice yields in Gujranwala Sheikhupura districts, Pakistan (Reports 006610), 1981 (Box 297)
  Paper to be presented at the forthcoming National Rice Seminar at Lahore.
  Pakistan Institute of Development Economics
  Program activities in the economicsof agriculture in Pakistan.
  15 p. + appendices: tables
  Production factors limiting rice yields ...
  Rice -- Research -- Pakistan -- Gujranwala District; Rice -- Research -- Pakistan -- Shekhupura District; Agricultural productivity -- Pakistan; Agricultural assistance -- Pakistan; Agriculture -- Economic aspects -- Pakistan; Endowments -- Pakistan -- Evaluation; Chaudhry, Abdul Majid, 1947-; Ashraf, Malik Muhammad; Rice Research Institute; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific
- A report to the Director General, Agricultural Research Council: some economic aspects of the government dairy farm (Reports 006611), 1977 (Box 297)
  Program activities in the economics of agriculture in Pakistan.
  Some economic aspects of the government dariy farm ...
  Dairy farms -- Pakistan; Livestock -- Research -- Pakistan; Milk yield -- Pakistan; Livestock productivity -- Pakistan; Agriculture -- Research -- Pakistan; Agriculture and state -- Pakistan; Goldman, Richard H.; Pakistan Institute of Development Economics
- Conference on "Feminine prespectives in social science research in Latin America," March 18-23, 1974 (Reports 006612) (Box 297)
  Memo to Robert Myers, dated April 30, 1974.
  6 p. + attachment
  Social sciences -- Research -- Latin America -- Congresses; Women -- Research -- Latin America -- Congresses; Manitzas, Nita R.; Ford Foundation. Latin America and the Caribbean
- Rice demonstration program for Punjab province for 1978 season (Reports 006613) (Box 297)
  Proposal for three demonstrations planned for the 1978 rice season in the Punjab Province: 1) insecticide, 2)plant population, and 3)fertilizer response.
  5 p. + appendices: ill., tables, chart
  Rice -- Yields -- India -- Punjab (India); Agricultural productivity -- India; Agricultural assistance -- India; Ross, Vernon E.; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific
- 1978 Rice Program and strategy for implementation (Reports 006614) (Box 297)
  Proposals for increasing rice yields in Pakistan.
  Rice -- Yields -- Pakistan; Agricultural productivity -- Pakistan; Agricultural assistance -- Pakistan; Ross, Vernon E.; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific
- The rice situation in Pakistan (Reports 006615), 1977 (Box 297)
  Problems and issues regarding rice production in Pakistan.
  Rice -- Yields -- Pakistan; Agricultural productivity -- Pakstan; Agriculture -- Economic aspects -- Pakistan; Ross, Vernon E.
- Incentives in the diffusion of family planning innovations (Reports 006616), 1971 (Box 297)
  As summarized by Everett M. Rogers and F. Floyd Shoemaker (1971), Communication of innovations: a cross-cultural approach, New York: Free Press. Synthesis of what is currently known about the role of incentives in the diffusion of family planning innovat
  37 p.
  Birth control -- India; Birth control research -- India; Communication in birth control -- India; Rogers, Everett M.; Baskara Rao, N., 1934-
- IICCROM (Reports 006617), 1979 (Box 297)
  International Center for the Study of the Preservation and Restoration of Cultural Property
  Cultural property -- Protection; Historic preservation -- Study and teaching; Antiquities -- Collection and preservation -- Study and teaching; Lyons, Elizabeth; International Centre for the Study of the Preservation and the Restoration of Cultural Property
- Quaid-I-Azam University department of Anthropology (Reports 006618), 1980 (Box 297)
  07700678
  Quaid-E-Azam University
  Training and research in the field of anthropology.
  6 p.: table
  Anthropology -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Pakistan; Anthropology -- Research -- Pakistan; Anthropologists -- Training of -- Pakistan; Universities and colleges -- Pakistan; Education, Higher -- Pakistan; Springer, J. (Jenny); Quaid-i-Azam University
- Western private organizations and East European dissent (Reports 006619), 1981 (Box 297)
  "Prepared for Conference on Dissent in Eastern Europe, Columbia University January 29-30, 1981." --T.p.
  European and International Affairs
  Non-governmental organizations -- Slavic countries -- Congresses; Non-governmental organizations -- Europe, Eastern; Dissenters -- Slavic countries -- Congresses; Dissenters -- Europe, Eastern; Human rights -- Europe, Eastern; Human rights -- Slavic countries; Gaer, Felice D.; Ford Foundation. Europe and International Affairs
- Suggested procedures for developing research projects on the economics of agriculture under the aegis of the Pakistan Agricultural Research Council (Reports 006620), 1976 (Box 297)
  Agriculture -- Research -- Pakistan; Agriculture and state -- Pakistan; Agriculture -- Economic aspects -- Pakistan; Goldman, Richard H.; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific
- The Ford Foundation's program in International Peace, Security and Arms Control (International Affairs Program) (Reports 006621), 1982 (Box 297)
  "Paper prepared for the Human Rights, Governance and International Affairs Committee of the Board of Trustees, Wednesday June 23, 1982." --T.p.
  Human Rights and Governance/International Affairs
  Peace -- Government policy -- Research; Security, International; Arms control -- International cooperation; International relations; National security; Schoettle, Enid C. B., 1939-; Ford Foundation. International Affairs
- International human rights efforts: Human Rights and Governance Program (Reports 006622), 1982 (Box 297)
  A discussion paper prepared for the Human Rights, Governance and International Affairs Committee of the Board of Trustees, June 23, 1982.
  Human Rights and Governance/United States and International Affairs Program
  Human rights -- Developing countries; Human rights -- United States; Civil rights -- Developing countries; Civil rights -- United States; Law reform -- Developing countries; Endowments -- Developing countries -- Evaluation; Philanthropy -- Developing countries; Forman, Shepard, 1938-; Bentsi-Enchill, Kwamena; Ford Foundation. International Affairs
- Neighborhood security and crime prevention (Reports 006623), 1982 (Box 297)
  Board of Trustees/USAI/Urban Poverty program/Human Rights and Governance
  Crime prevention -- United States; Criminal justice, Administration of -- Citizen participation -- United States; Police-community relations -- United States; Arson -- United States; Ford Foundation. Human Rights and Governance
- Funding opportunities in reproductive biology and contraceptive development (Reports 006624), 1974 (Box 297)
  Memo to David Bell, dated June 27, 1974.
  Fertility, Human -- Research; Contraceptives -- Research; Birth control research; Population assistance; Mahoney, Richard T.; Ford Foundation. Population Program
- Improving secondary schools and related programs: A status report (Reports 006625), 1982 (Box 298)